{
    "id": "92307b2a67db4c34bf416660d4ddb63a",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Sam ………………………… out every morning.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about habitual actions.",
            "answers": [
                "work",
                "works",
                "is working"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9d87dec6316e49f8a36b4106b35453c8"
        },
        {
            "question": "Every child …………………………….. love.",
            "description": "We use a singular verb after each and every. ",
            "answers": [
                "need",
                "needs",
                "is needing",
                "has needed"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "0a16425509a843d5b21e4cee174e3145"
        },
        {
            "question": "I once ……………………………. to a concert.",
            "description": "The simple past is used to talk about finished events.",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "have gone",
                "went"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "28947d62fca940b98cfb6c18b564f398"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………………. a strange experience yesterday.",
            "description": "Had is the past tense form of has/have.",
            "answers": [
                "had",
                "did",
                "was"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "28ebe8dd957940188fd90e274182856f"
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………….. a chance to meet them when I was in America.",
            "description": "Here the clause when I was in America clearly indicates that we are talking about past time. ",
            "answers": [
                "got",
                "have got",
                "get"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "f982f28658134b3d8d9c471400ea680a"
        },
        {
            "question": "The teacher ……………………………………. the child on the back.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "pat",
                "patted",
                "has patted"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "18fd3753675e4a198a7bf6e031b7dff1"
        },
        {
            "question": "The lakes …………………………… up in summer.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about facts and general truths. ",
            "answers": [
                "dry",
                "dries",
                "are drying"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b63922491b7241e9a1ebad16d573767f"
        },
        {
            "question": "Kind words …………………………… others joy.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "give",
                "gave",
                "have given"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b7f6cb9eb5c340a68bb62bc49221f96d"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she ………………………………. now, we would be in trouble.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "arrives",
                "arrived",
                "has arrived"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "adedf9501b9b4dc385d9f614538ea6c4"
        },
        {
            "question": "He took out his pen and ………………………………… writing.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "started",
                "start",
                "starts"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "0193bf55f07f44b7bec57a0094763399"
        },
        {
            "question": "He who ……………………………… hard will certainly succeed.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "works",
                "worked",
                "has worked"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "71c334f5b9ac4f7eac38ede5899ce3b9"
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………… the parcel in the morning.",
            "description": "The simple past is more common with the time expression in the morning. ",
            "answers": [
                "received",
                "have received",
                "had received"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "1cfe01589287443faa365e6d1d7c9209"
        }
    ]
}